A Guide to the Records of Roanoke Drug Company 1916-1964
Roanoke Public Libraries
Roanoke Public Libraries
A Guide to the Records of Roanoke Drug Company
Roanoke Public Libraries
2005.9.13
1 record storage box and 1 short lid "shoebox"
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Richard and Carol Conway
Historical Note
Roanoke Drug Company has a long and complex history. Commercial druggist companies boomed in the 19th and 20th centuries. One such company that began during this time was Benton, Myers, and Company formed in Cleveland, Ohio. In 1884, Benton Myers merged with the Hall-Van Gorder Company. Meanwhile, in Roanoke, the Bowles-Robertson Drug Company had a shop in downtown Roanoke on Salem Avenue. In late 1916, the name changed from Bowles-Robertson to Roanoke Drug Company. It would remain Roanoke Drug Company until 1929, when drug conglomerate, McKesson-Robbins took over after merging with Hall-Van Gorder the previous year, in 1928. Many of the records have Dorothy Layman’s name on them. Ms. Layman began working at Bowles-Robertson while in her 20s. She later married and became Dorothy Cline, as some of the memos indicate. She was the only female accountant and office manager the company ever employed
Scope and Content
This collection is comprised of office memos, photographs, news clippings, meeting minutes, stock ledger books, office directories and artifacts.
Arrangement
Documents are arranged alphabetically by document type with all artifacts housed in Box 2.
Contents List
- Records (Box 1)
  - Bowles-Robertson meeting memos undated (Folder 1)
  - "Debits and Credits": accountant newsletters 1949-1952 (Folder 2)
  - Group photographs 1959 and 1965 (Folder 3)
  - Insurance policy for Roanoke Drug Company date unknown (Folder 4)
  - Interoffice memos 1934-1964 (Folder 5)
  - McKesson and Robbins Employee Report 1942 (Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous ephemera from various drug companies undated (Folder 7)
  - Newspaper articles on related drug companies various dates (Folder 8)
  - Office directories 1914-1937 (Folder 9)
  - Office directories 1939-1948 (Folder 10)
  - Ohio State Pharmaceutical Association Meeting Book 1893 (Folder 11)
  - Stocks issued undated (Folder 12)
  - Bowles-Robertson Stock Ledger Book undated (Folder 13)
  - Roanoke Drug Company Stock Ledger Book undated (Folder 14)
- Artifacts (Box 2)
  - Tawn Lightweights Travel Kit undated (Item 1)
  - Tawn Shaving Set undated (Item 2)
  - Mennen's Centennial Collection Aftershave 1978 (Item 3)
  - Tawn Ladies Travel Kit undated (Item 4)